<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Expert Full-stack Web Developer - Custom Themes and Apps by bashr.me on Got an interesting project in mind? I'm a Full-stack Shopify developer</title><link>https://bashr.me/</link><description>Recent content in Expert Full-stack Web Developer - Custom Themes and Apps by bashr.me on Got an interesting project in mind? I'm a Full-stack Shopify developer</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 11:58:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://bashr.me/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Breaking Shopify with custom URL parameters using Liquid only!</title><link>https://bashr.me/articles/custom-url-parameters-using-liquid/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 11:58:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://bashr.me/articles/custom-url-parameters-using-liquid/</guid><description>&lt;p>If you&amp;rsquo;ve ever done backend web development, you&amp;rsquo;ve probably had to construct your own API endpoints, allowing for URL parameter inputs that can be used in your website/webapp.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As a dedicated Shopify developer, I&amp;rsquo;ve always wondered if I could somehow do the same in the Shopify ecosystem without the use of any third-party tools, which I&amp;rsquo;ve successfully done using a novelty method I&amp;rsquo;ve talked about in &lt;a href="https://bashr.me/articles/password-protected-pages-without-locksmith/">my previous article&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this article, I&amp;rsquo;ll be expanding on that idea by providing another use case for a recent Shopify project I was tasked with.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How to password protect pages in Shopify without Locksmith</title><link>https://bashr.me/articles/password-protected-pages-without-locksmith/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 12:40:09 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://bashr.me/articles/password-protected-pages-without-locksmith/</guid><description>&lt;p>If you run a Shopify store, you might find yourself having to password protect a page you&amp;rsquo;d like to reserve only for specific customers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Perhaps it&amp;rsquo;s a pricing page for collaborators, or exclusive business updates you&amp;rsquo;d like to share with a select few high-value customers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you found this article by google something like &amp;ldquo;How to password protect a page in Shopify&amp;rdquo;, expecting a built-in Shopify feature, you&amp;rsquo;d be disappointed to find out that most results refer you to some Shopify app that provides this seemingly primitive function.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Maximizing Your Shopify Store's Search Engine: How to Improve Search Results to Compete with AI-Powered Apps</title><link>https://bashr.me/articles/maximizing-your-shopify-stores-search-engine-how-to-improve-search-results-to-compete-with-aipowered-apps/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2023 18:09:00 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://bashr.me/articles/maximizing-your-shopify-stores-search-engine-how-to-improve-search-results-to-compete-with-aipowered-apps/</guid><description>&lt;p>All merchants will agree that Shopify isn&amp;rsquo;t perfect out of the box. For example, the standard Shopify predictive search function feels off or incomplete to many merchants, which makes &amp;ldquo;AI-powered&amp;rdquo; search engines popular on the Shopify app store.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We try, wherever possible, to replace bulky Shopify apps with leaner, standard solutions, and in this guide, we&amp;rsquo;ll explore just how we did that to improve one of our client&amp;rsquo;s predictive search.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Shopify Liquid for Non-Tech-Savvy Merchants and Beginners</title><link>https://bashr.me/articles/shopify-liquid-template-language-a-comprehensive-guide-for-non-tech-savvy-merchants-and-beginners/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2023 11:40:07 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://bashr.me/articles/shopify-liquid-template-language-a-comprehensive-guide-for-non-tech-savvy-merchants-and-beginners/</guid><description>&lt;p>Learning the basics of Liquid can help you stay out of the dark and be unafraid to touch code. After all, your theme and all the code in it are also part of your business.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>While it may seem purely technical, Liquid is a relatively human-readable programming language. Most non-tech-savvy merchants can easily understand it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this guide, I&amp;rsquo;ll try to explain Liquid at a very primitive level to provide a strong understanding of the technology that runs our storefronts.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How to create a quick Instagram feed for your Shopify store</title><link>https://bashr.me/articles/quick-dirty-instagram-feed-your-shopify-store/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2023 14:56:09 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://bashr.me/articles/quick-dirty-instagram-feed-your-shopify-store/</guid><description>&lt;h5 id="tldr-shut-up-and-give-me-the-code">tl;dr (shut up and give me the code)&lt;/h5>
&lt;p>You can find the final version of the code down below.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>When I&amp;rsquo;m drafting something up or even creating &lt;a href="https://bashr.me/projects/made-by-pivot/">an entire custom Shopify theme&lt;/a>, I&amp;rsquo;m often asked to include an Instagram feed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>While installing some app is the go-to answer for many developers, it is not without its drawbacks;&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>It hurts site load speed&lt;/li>
&lt;li>It&amp;rsquo;s usually inconsistent with the rest of the theme&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Advanced customization is usually not possible&lt;/li>
&lt;li>You can&amp;rsquo;t customize directly from the theme editor&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>In this short guide, I&amp;rsquo;m going to share how I usually do it while avoiding the above drawbacks.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How to improve your Shopify store’s server response time</title><link>https://bashr.me/articles/improve-your-shopify-stores-server-response-time-using-ajax-cart-api/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2023 14:56:09 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://bashr.me/articles/improve-your-shopify-stores-server-response-time-using-ajax-cart-api/</guid><description>&lt;p>If you&amp;rsquo;re running a Shopify store, you know how important it is to have fast load times. Slow websites can result in lost sales and frustrated customers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Fortunately, with the release of Shopify 2.0 came the added feature of rendering sections using the AJAX Cart API, which (with some clever engineering) can be used to improve your store&amp;rsquo;s server response times.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this article, I&amp;rsquo;ll share how I use the AJAX Cart API to &lt;a href="https://bashr.me/projects/">create fast Shopify themes&lt;/a> for my clients .&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Made by Pivot | Project Case Study by bashr.me</title><link>https://bashr.me/projects/made-by-pivot/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2023 14:56:09 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://bashr.me/projects/made-by-pivot/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Marc Gebauer Lifestyle | Project Case Study by bashr.me</title><link>https://bashr.me/projects/marc-gebauer/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2023 14:56:09 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://bashr.me/projects/marc-gebauer/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Prestige Titles PDF Generator | Project Case Study by bashr.me</title><link>https://bashr.me/projects/prestige-titles-pdf-generator/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2023 14:56:09 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://bashr.me/projects/prestige-titles-pdf-generator/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Winslow Style Tailoring | Project Case Study by bashr.me</title><link>https://bashr.me/projects/winslow-style/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2023 14:56:09 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://bashr.me/projects/winslow-style/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>